https://www.sprint-electric.com/cookies-privacy/

[Skip to Content]
Select language
Select language
Call now:
PRIVACY POLICY
Sprint Electric Limited (referred to hereinafter as “we” or “Sprint Electric”) will always adhere to UK Data Protection Legislation, which, from 25 May 2018, includes EU Regulation 2016/679 General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).
The following Privacy Policy explains what happens to any personal data that you provide to us, or that we collect from you whilst you visit our site, and how we use cookies on this website.
This Privacy Policy was last updated on 21 May 2018.
Information that we collect from the website
In running and maintaining our website we may collect and process the following data about you:
Information about your use of our site including details of your visits such as pages viewed and the resources that you access. Such information includes traffic data, location data and other communication data. The extent and type of information we receive from you on our website depends on what you do when visiting our site. If you visit our site to read or download information, such as product information or articles, all of the information we collect – such as the domain from which you access the Internet, the date and time you access our site, and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site – is not personally identifiable. Information about the number of visitors and their use of the site and is only used for statistical purposes (in aggregate form) to make our site more useful and attractive to you.
Information provided voluntarily by you. For example, when you register for information or make a purchase and/or information that you provide when you communicate with us by any means. Example: if you provide us with personal data we will use it to process your online requests, to provide goods and services to you or your organisation and to let you know about other Sprint Electric products and services in which you might be interested.
Information that we may collect from other sources
From time to time we may gather business contact information for individuals working in certain business corporations which we consider to be manufacturers or producers of machines, systems and / or products which contain variable speed drives. The information collected comprises: Contact Full Name, Company, Business Telephone Number, Business Email Address, Job Title, Job Function, Company Address.
This information is gathered by in-person request, from public sources, from our website enquiry form or from reputable third party data providers. Sprint Electric does not collect any non-business-related data such as date of birth, gender, home address, personal email, personal mobile number, or government identification number.
Sprint Electric processes this information for direct marketing purposes in the legitimate interest of itself.
Sprint Electric does not process sensitive data information related to individual consumers.
Sprint Electric understands the importance of protecting children’s privacy, especially in an online environment. Our site is designed specifically for adults in a business context and is not intentionally designed for or directed at minors younger than 18 years of age. It is our policy never to knowingly collect or maintain information about anyone under the age of 18.
Storing Your Personal Data
Data is stored on UK servers accessible via cloud-based services.  We do our utmost to ensure that all reasonable steps are taken to make sure that your data is stored safely and securely.
Data is also used by Sprint Electric for business-to-business marketing in the legitimate interest of itself and is processed and stored using Campaign Monitor – please see their Privacy Policy.
Data sent by you personally via our website may require the transfer of data outside of the European Union. By providing your personal data to us, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing. The sending of information via the Internet is not totally secure, and on occasion, such information can be intercepted. We cannot guarantee the security of data that you choose to send us electronically and hence is entirely at your own risk.
Use of Your Information
We use the information that we collect from you to provide our goods and services to you.  We will not sell, rent or trade your personal data with other companies for marketing purposes.
In addition to this we may use the information for any of the following purposes:
To provide information to you that you request from us relating to our products or services.
To provide information to you relating to other products that may be of interest to you.
To inform you of any changes to our website, services or goods and products
If you have previously purchased goods or services from us we may provide to you details of similar goods or services, or other goods and services, that you may be interested in.
Direct business to business marketing where Sprint Electric has a legitimate interest to communicate with decision makers in business organisations which procure to design or manufacture machines, systems and products that may use variable speed drives: Sprint Electric may use the information to contact individuals on their business telephone or at their business email address in order to market products and/or services to the individual’s employer company.
We will not use the information to harass or otherwise violate any law or any person’s rights, and may only use the information for direct marketing purposes with a legitimate interest.
When we process your personal information for our legitimate interests, we make sure to consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative), and your rights under data protection law.  Our legitimate business interests do not automatically override your interests – we will not use your Personal Data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law).
Protection of personal data
We will not disclose your personal information to any other party other than in accordance with this Privacy Policy and in the circumstances detailed below:
An actual or potential buyer (and its agents and advisers) in connection with an actual or proposed purchase, merger or acquisition of any part of our business.
Where we are legally required by law to disclose your personal information.
To further fraud protection and reduce the risk of fraud.
Information Security
Sprint Electric maintains suitable safeguards, including reasonable physical, administrative and technical safeguards to protect its database from unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration or destruction.
Periodic Validation
Sprint Electric seeks to re-verify the accuracy of all the information on a periodic basis by refreshing our database through phone and email validation. Data that is found to be inaccurate or out of date is updated in our database.
Your personal information will be retained only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected or as required by law.
Third Party Links
On occasion we include links to third parties on this website. Where we provide a link it does not mean that we endorse or approve that site’s policy towards visitor privacy. You should review their privacy policy before sending them any personal data.
Access to Personal Information
With respect to the information Sprint Electric possesses about you, you have the right:
to access
to rectification
to deletion
to restrict processing of your personal data
to object to processing
to data portability
to be informed
related to automated decision making and profiling
You may exercise any of these rights  and/or amend or update your personal information or request us to stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes by contacting us at info@sprint-electric.com.
If you’re not happy with how we are processing your personal data, please let us know by sending an email to info@sprint-electric.com. We will review and investigate your complaint, and try to get back to you within a reasonable time frame. You can also complain to your local data protection authority. They will be able to advise you how to submit a complaint.
Use of Cookies
Cookies provide information regarding the computer used by a visitor. We may use cookies where appropriate to gather information about your computer in order to assist us in improving our website.
We may gather information about your general Internet use by using the cookie. Where used, these cookies are downloaded to your computer and stored on the computer’s hard drive. Such information will not identify you personally; it is statistical data that does not identify any personal details whatsoever.
You can adjust the settings on your computer to decline any cookies if you wish. This can be done within the “settings” section of your computer. For more information please read the advice at www.aboutcookies.org.uk.
What are cookies?
Cookies are small text files containing a string of characters that can be placed on your computer or mobile device that uniquely identify your browser or device.
What are cookies used for?
Cookies allow a site or services to know if your computer or device has visited that site or service before. Cookies can then be used to help understand how the site or service is being used, help you navigate between pages efficiently, help remember your preferences, and generally improve your browsing experience. Cookies can also help ensure marketing you see online is more relevant to you and your interests.
What cookies does this site use?
WordPress (1st Party) – We use WordPress to run this site and this uses Cookies to further enhance the experience of the website, which you can read more about, here.
Google Analytics (3rd party) – We use this to see how many visitors we are getting, and how they found us. You can find out more about Google Analytics’ Cookies here.
First and third party cookies
First-party cookies are cookies that belong to this site; third-party cookies are cookies that another party places on your device through our Service. Third-party cookies may be placed on your device by someone providing a service for us – for example, to help us understand how our service is being used.
How to control and delete cookies
If you want to delete cookies follow the instructions here.
If you wish to disable your browser from receiving cookies follow the instructions here.
Note that if you set your browser to disable cookies, you may not be able to access certain parts of our Service and other parts of our Service may not work properly.
You can find out more information cookie settings at third-party information sites, such as this one.
Contacting Us
Please do not hesitate to contact us regarding any matter relating to this Privacy Policy via email at info@sprint-electric.com.
Copyright Notice
All content of this website, including content in any form whatsoever, is owned by Sprint Electric Limited. All rights are reserved.
TALK TO A DRIVES EXPERT
Not sure which of our products offers the best solution for you? Why not get in touch with one of our drives experts? Our experienced team can talk through your requirements and answer any questions you might have.
GET IN TOUCH
SPRINT WORLDWIDE
Local sales & support from 70 carefully selected approved partners in over 40 countries.
Search NOW
BROWSE OUR RESOURCES
Find product brochures and datasheets, download supporting software or browse our FAQs
DownloadsProduct Brochures
Manuals
Datasheets & GUIDES
Glossary
PopularCONTACT US
PRODUCT SELECTOR
About Sprint Electric
Product Overview
Login
My basket (0)
Select Your Products
Back to Top
Find Distributor
×
Privacy Policy
This site tracks visits anonymously using cookies – close this dialog to confirm you are happy with that, or find out more in our privacy policy
Agree & Close
CLOSE
Request Pricing
Please complete form bellow
Product*Name*Email*
Telephone Number*Company*Country*-- Select country --AfghanistanAlbaniaAlgeriaAmerican SamoaAndorraAngolaAntigua and BarbudaArgentinaArmeniaAustraliaAustriaAzerbaijanBahamasBahrainBangladeshBarbadosBelarusBelgiumBelizeBeninBermudaBhutanBoliviaBosnia and HerzegovinaBotswanaBrazilBruneiBulgariaBurkina FasoBurundiCambodiaCameroonCanadaCape VerdeCayman IslandsCentral African RepublicChadChileChinaColombiaComorosCongo, Democratic Republic of theCongo, Republic of theCosta RicaCôte d'IvoireCroatiaCubaCuraçaoCyprusCzech RepublicDenmarkDjiboutiDominicaDominican RepublicEast TimorEcuadorEgyptEl SalvadorEquatorial GuineaEritreaEstoniaEthiopiaFaroe IslandsFijiFinlandFranceFrench PolynesiaGabonGambiaGeorgiaGermanyGhanaGreeceGreenlandGrenadaGuamGuatemalaGuineaGuinea-BissauGuyanaHaitiHondurasHong KongHungaryIcelandIndiaIndonesiaIranIraqIrelandIsraelItalyJamaicaJapanJordanKazakhstanKenyaKiribatiNorth KoreaSouth KoreaKosovoKuwaitKyrgyzstanLaosLatviaLebanonLesothoLiberiaLibyaLiechtensteinLithuaniaLuxembourgMacedoniaMadagascarMalawiMalaysiaMaldivesMaliMaltaMarshall IslandsMauritaniaMauritiusMexicoMicronesiaMoldovaMonacoMongoliaMontenegroMoroccoMozambiqueMyanmarNamibiaNauruNepalNetherlandsNew ZealandNicaraguaNigerNigeriaNorthern Mariana IslandsNorwayOmanPakistanPalauPalestine, State ofPanamaPapua New GuineaParaguayPeruPhilippinesPolandPortugalPuerto RicoQatarRomaniaRussiaRwandaSaint Kitts and NevisSaint LuciaSaint Vincent and the GrenadinesSamoaSan MarinoSao Tome and PrincipeSaudi ArabiaSenegalSerbiaSeychellesSierra LeoneSingaporeSint MaartenSlovakiaSloveniaSolomon IslandsSomaliaSouth AfricaSpainSri LankaSudanSudan, SouthSurinameSwazilandSwedenSwitzerlandSyriaTaiwanTajikistanTanzaniaThailandTogoTongaTrinidad and TobagoTunisiaTurkeyTurkmenistanTuvaluUgandaUkraineUnited Arab EmiratesUnited KingdomUnited StatesUruguayUzbekistanVanuatuVatican CityVenezuelaVietnamVirgin Islands, BritishVirgin Islands, U.S.YemenZambiaZimbabweMessage*HUMAN TEST
×
